《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
警察绝不会允许你接近盖勒文的
Cops aren't gonna let you within a hundred feet of Galavan.
让我们替你杀了他吧
Let us whack him for you.
不行
No.
他是我的
He's mine.
打死他  警探
Shoot him, Detective.
他杀了我母亲  吉姆
He killed my mother, Jim.
你抓到韦恩家的男孩了吗
You have the Wayne boy?
还没呢
Not yet.
有些实际问题还有待解决
There are some practical matters that have to be resolved first.
看到这根手指了吗
See this finger?
我手指一勾  小布鲁斯就会跟我走
I've got little Bruce wrapped tight around it.
我杀他是因为他打你
I had to kill him because he hit you.
我爱你
I love you.
柯丽丝汀  柯丽丝汀
Kristen? Kristen?
不
No.
不到一年  我和吉姆就会复合
Within a year, Jim and I will be back together.
想知道为什么吗
Want to know why?
因为我们是一样的
Because we're both the same.
我们都有阴暗面
We both have a dark side.
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译  最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译 木浅   小胖纸Amy   小酸奶!   DustD   大K
翻译 Silence   盐湖凉开水   charcie   草草
时间轴 风吹来的那片云
后期 宝宝   校对 草草   总监 草草
准备好彩排了吗
Ready for the practice run?
我都想跳过这一步直接结婚了
I'm ready to skip this and get married.
我也是
Me, too.
排练一遍誓言吧
Let us rehearse the vows.
芭芭拉·基恩
Barbara Kean...
你是否愿意让詹姆斯·戈登
do you take James Gordon
做你不被法律认可的丈夫  并永远
to be your unlawfully wedded husband to have and to hold...
抱歉  神父  你说成了"不被法律认可"
I'm sorry, Father. You said "unlawfully wedded."
芭芭拉
Barbara,
拜托  你就说是就行了
just answer him, for God's sake.
快说呀
I'm waiting.
芭芭拉
Barbara,
你怎么了
what's wrong?
你怎么做到的呀
How did you do that?
噩梦啊
Bad dream.
芭芭拉
就是今天
爱你  盖
当了市长不是应该能多睡会儿吗
Doesn't being mayor mean you can sleep in?
吉姆·戈登逼得我们不得不加快计划进度
Jim Gordon has forced us to accelerate our plans.
也该加快了
About time.
今天早上我要见布鲁斯·韦恩
I'll meet with Bruce Wayne this morning.
如果顺利  到晚上他的公司就是我的了
If all goes well, I'll have his company by the end of the day.
我还是不明白你打算怎么让布鲁斯·韦恩
I still don't see how you can get Bruce Wayne
就这么交出家族事业
to turn over his family's legacy.
你可没那么有魅力
You're not that charming.
我要拿这世上他最想要的东西和他换
I'm going to offer him the thing he wants most in the world.
不过
Still,
还是比较悬
it will be delicate.
吉姆·戈登不能来搅局
Jim Gordon must not be allowed to interfere.
但如果他突然死掉会影响布鲁斯的心情
But his sudden death would upset Bruce.
所以得把他引开
So we need him distracted,
缠住他
occupied,
然后
and then...
你告诉她了吗
Have you told her?
告诉我什么
Told me what?
我好喜欢我的礼物
I love my present.
是不是我想那个的意思
Does it mean what I think it does?
是的  亲爱的
Yes, my dear.
今天
Today is the day
你可以杀掉吉姆·戈登了
you get to kill Jim Gordon.
阿卡姆劫狱
The breakout at Arkham,
哥谭市警局屠杀
the massacre of the GCPD,
晚会屠杀  系列纵火案
the gala, the arsons,
都是盖勒文
it was Galavan.
全是他一手策划的
He's behind everything.
你有证据证明吗
And you have proof of this?
有企鹅  还有吉尔兹的供词
I have Penguin, and I have Gilzean.
都是罪犯
Both criminals.
都无处可寻
Both in the wind.
鉴于我取得这些情报的情形
Given the circumstances under which I obtained the information,
我可以肯定他们说的是实话
I think it's safe to say they were telling the truth.
或许他们说的是实话
Maybe they are.
但是你没有合法证据  没有证明
But you have no legal evidence, no proof,
没有一条可靠线索可查
not a single hard lead to go on.
就凭你现在手头上的证据把盖勒文带来
You bring in Galavan with what you have now,
他只会嘲笑你
and he'll just laugh at you.
他得意不了多久
He won't laugh long.
你们打算对他动粗吗
Are you gonna rough him up a little?
非法拷打  是这么个计划吗
Lawless thuggery, is that your plan?
你想要逮捕盖勒文吗
You want to arrest Galavan?
那就做好警察的本职工作
You do the police work
给我找些确凿证据来
and you bring me back some real proof.
能怪他吗
Can you blame him?
你要追查的人昨天刚当选市长
You're going after a man who was elected mayor yesterday.
他是哥谭最受欢迎的人
The most popular figure in Gotham.
盖勒文有问题
Galavan is dirty.
我敢拿我的性命打赌
I'd bet my life on it.
-不要  -不要什么
- Well, don't. - Don't what?
不要拿自己的性命打赌
Don't bet your life on it.
我了解你那种眼神  吉姆
I know that look in your eye, Jim.
冷静些
Be cool.
别把这事搞成私人恩怨
Do not make this personal.
这就是私人恩怨  不是吗
Well, it is personal, isn't it?
-除非是你自己搞成那样  -疑犯  疑犯
- Only if you make it that way. - Suspect! Suspect!
把手放到我能看见的地方
Put your hands where I can see them!
别动
Right there!
你好  吉姆
Hi, Jim.
好久不见
Long time no see.
哥谭
第二季  第八集
你说只愿和我谈
You said you'd only talk to me.
我听着呢
I'm listening.
没错
Yes.
听好了
Here it is.
能不能给我来杯拿铁或是什么的
Is there any chance I could get a latte or something?
这不是游戏  芭芭拉
This is not a game, Barbara.
当然是了
Of course it is.
一场你一直在输的游戏
It's a game you've been losing.
而且输大了
Big-time.
这不是游戏
It is not a game.
一定折磨死你了
It must be killing you.
你的义愤填膺无处可发泄
All that righteous indignation with no place to go.
你为什么要来这里
Why are you here?
不要表现得那么平静  一本正经
Don't act all calm and businesslike.
如果你想的话  对我动粗啊
Rough me up a little, if you want.
我不想那么做
I don't want to do that.
我不想伤害你
I don't want to hurt you.
我想帮你
I want to help you.
我知道...
I know...
你是想伤害我的
you want to hurt me,
有那么一点吧
just a little.
我最近很不乖
I've been a very bad girl.
不
No.
你是个好女人
You're a good woman.
你只是病了而已
You're just sick, is all.
我就知道
I knew it.
我就知道你对我还有感觉
I knew you still had feelings for me.
我当然有感觉了
Of course I have feelings.
跟我说说
Talk to me.
好的
I will.
但首先我想给你看点东西
But first I want to show you something.
不远  不会花太久
It's not far away, won't take long.
什么东西
Well, what is it?
你想给我看什么
What do you want to show me?
是个惊喜
It's a surprise.
别担心  是个好惊喜
Don't worry, it's a good one.
之后  我会告诉你一切
And then after that, I will tell you everything.
一切什么
Everything about what?
关于阿卡姆劫狱吗
Is it about the breakout at Arkham?
是盖勒文干的吗
Was it Galavan?
你当然想知道了
Wouldn't you like to know?
戈登警探
Detective Gordon?
是我的律师到了
Okay, that's someone telling you that my lawyer is here.
给你五分钟考虑一下吧
Why don't you take five minutes to think about it?
戈登警探  时间到了
Detective Gordon, time's up.
她在玩什么把戏
What is she playing at?
不知道  长官
Not sure, sir.
我建议我们跟她玩下去  查清楚
I suggest we play along and find out.
我去看看她想给我看什么
I'll go see this thing she wants to show me.
吉姆  她精神有问题
Jim, she's mentally ill.
才不呢  她清醒得很
Like hell. She's sharp as a nail.
这是一个陷阱
This is a trap.
不管怎样  这都太冒险了
Yeah. Either way, it's too risky.
我们还有什么选择
What choice do we have, huh?
她不肯说
She won't talk.
亲她也没有用  对吗
And kissing her didn't work out, did it?
那是我的判断决定  长官
That was a judgment call, sir.
判断  是吗
Judgment? Really?
我们先把注意力放在眼前的问题上
Let's focus on the issue at hand.
作为首席验尸官  我的专业意见是
It's my official opinion as chief medical examiner
基恩小姐有严重的精神问题
that Miss Kean is seriously mentally ill
应该送进医院  接受治疗
and should be in a hospital, getting treatment.
没错  明天再送
Yes. Tomorrow.
我建议咱们顺水推舟
Look, I suggest we play along,
让她觉得自己控制了局势
let her think she's in control.
我可以在车上继续做她工作
I can still work on her inside the car.
也许能问出些有用信息
Maybe I can find out something useful.
她是可能引向盖勒文的唯一线索
She's our only link to Galavan.
值得冒这个险
It's worth the risk.
好吧  去做吧
All right, do it.
抱歉  柯林格小姐
Sorry, Miss Kringle.
你有客  圣克劳德小姐
You have a visitor, Miss St. Cloud.
你好
Hello.
我叔叔等下就来
My uncle will be just a moment.
让你久等了他很抱歉
He wanted me to apologize for keeping you waiting.
没事的
It's fine.
你知道他为什么想见我吗
Do you have any idea why he wanted to see me?
他告诉我他有东西要给你
He told me he had something for you.
他可兴奋了  一副傻样
He seemed excited. It was totally goofy.
我想象不出他也会有"傻样"
I can't picture him goofy.
很抱歉让你久等了
I am so sorry to keep you waiting.
等会儿见
I'll see you later.
再见
Bye.
请吧
Please.
见见突击队的新成员
Meet the new crop of Strike Force members.
我们要派他们深入火线  但他们已经准备好了
We're throwing them in the deep end, but they're ready.
他们会在战术指挥车中尾随你们
They'll be shadowing you in a TAC SUV.
我会在这里监控实况
I'll be monitoring from here.
一旦出现我认为不妙的情况
The second I don't like something,
我就终止行动  明白了吗
I'm pulling the plug-- agreed?
是  长官
Yes, sir.
戈登
Gordon?
明白
Agreed.
这事对他来说太情绪化
He's too wrapped up in this thing emotionally.
我需要确保你们中至少有一个
I need to know that one of you isn't gonna get sucked into
不会被基恩小姐的伎俩迷惑住
all these mind games that Ms. Kean is gonna be pulling out there.
别担心  从没有人能说
Not to worry-- no one's ever accused me
我会被伎俩迷惑
of getting sucked into mind games.
遵从我的命令  明白吗
Just follow my orders, understood?
明白  警监
Understood, Captain.
很高兴咱们有机会聊聊
I'm glad we had this chance to talk.
听着
Hey, look.
事情变成这样我也不愿意
I don't like this any more than you do.
但这是唯一的办法
But it is the only way.
不  这是你  吉姆
No, this is you, Jim.
这就是你的意思
This is all you.
她又把你拽回去了  对不对
She sucked you right back in, didn't she?
因为她对你还有影响
Because she still has a hold on you.
她的病态与你的相互依存
Her sickness and yours feed off each other.
什么意思  我的病态  我没病
What do you mean, my sickness? I'm not sick.
你看见万丈深渊  便飞奔过去
You see an abyss, and you run toward it.
这不健康
That's not healthy.
我不过是尽职罢了
I'm just doing my job.
行动
Moving out!
小莱
Hey, Lee.
你不介意我借他一会儿吧
You don't mind if I borrow him for a little while, do you?
我想问你个问题
I want to ask you a question.
如果你可以实现一个梦想
If you could have one dream come true,
那会是什么
what would that be?
找到杀死我父母的凶手
I would find the man who killed my parents.
如果你找到他  会怎么处理他
What would you do if you found him?
我会杀了他
I would kill him.
很有血性嘛
What a young tiger you are.
我的梦想
My dream?
就是拯救这座城市
I would save this city.
铲除哥谭的腐败势力
I would rid Gotham of corruption,
打击犯罪
crime
让市民富起来
and poverty.
听起来不错
Sounds good.
你打算怎么做
How would you do that?
我有很多计划  方案
Oh, I have plans, schemes,
想法理念
ideas aplenty.
但我需要帮助
But... I need help.
需要你的帮助
I need your help.
愿意效劳
Of course.
作为报答  我可以你帮你
And perhaps in return, I could help you
实现你的愿望
with your dream.
怎么说
How so?
疏通道路
Get those vehicles out of the way!
没问题吧
You good?
只要是让巴恩斯警监紧张的事
Anything that makes Captain Barnes' tight ass nervous,
我都支持
I'm all for.
小心别碰头
Watch your head.
我们现在要去哪呢
So, you want to tell us where we're going?
去市中心
Head downtown.
布鲁斯  你们家参与建造了这座城市
Bruce, your family helped build this city.
韦恩这个姓氏就是
The Wayne name is synonymous with
成长  力量和繁荣的代名词
growth, strength and prosperity.
但也是个谎言
It's also a lie.
此话怎讲
Please explain what you mean.
我调查韦恩集团很长时间了
I've been investigating Wayne Enterprises for quite some time.
知道我查出了什么吗
You know what I found?
有毒废料倾倒
Toxic waste dumps.
非法军火合同
Illegal weapons contracts.
使用违禁化学品
Use of banned chemicals.
恶梦般的实验
Nightmarish experiments.
不能再继续了
It can't continue.
请你明白
Please, understand
腐败不是重点
this isn't about corruption.
重点是拯救无辜者
It's about saving innocent lives.
我向你保证
You have my word.
我会仔细调查的
I will look into all of it.
并且会制止责任人
And I will stop whoever's responsible.
不  布鲁斯  你不会的
No, Bruce, you won't.
你做不到
You can't.
大家经常小看我
People often underestimate me.
韦恩集团
Wayne Enterprises
是一家价值数十亿美元的企业集团
is a multi-billion-dollar conglomerate,
还有一个会为保护秘密而不惜杀人的董事会
with a board that will kill to protect its secrets.
谁说我小看你了
Who's underestimating you?
你为什么和我说这些
Why are you telling me this?
显然你有想提出的解决办法
You obviously have a solution you want to propose.
你控制韦恩集团51%的表决权股份
You control 51% of the voting shares of Wayne Enterprises.
如果你把股份卖给我
If you sell me your shares,
我就能接管  做该做之事
I could take control, do what needs to be done.
你就会成为自由的现金亿万富翁
You would be a cash billionaire with freedom.
你想要我的公司
You want my company?
我想要清理哥谭市
I want to clean up Gotham.
保护市民
Protect its citizens.
恢复这座城市原本的样子
Return the city to what it was.
但没有你帮忙  我做不到
But I can't do it without your help.
韦恩集团是我的责任
Wayne Enterprises is my responsibility.
是我父母唯一的遗产
It's all I have left of them.
我的价码不只是钱  布鲁斯
I'm not just offering you money, Bruce.
你父母被杀的那晚
The night your parents were killed,
你本不该出现在那儿吧
you weren't supposed to be there, were you?
对
No.
你父母本想去戏院
Your parents were headed for the theater.
你父亲改了主意
Your father changed his mind.
提出去看电影
Suggested a movie.
还叫上了你
Invited you along.
你们去迟了
You got there late.
这事我从未和人说过
I've never told anybody that.
那晚他在跟踪你父亲
He was following your father that night.
早在进入小巷之前
Before the alleyway.
我是个有不少资源的人
I'm a man of considerable resources.
即使如此
Even then,
也还是调查了好久
it took some doing.
所以我昨晚没说什么
It's why I didn't want to say anything last night.
直到今天我才确认
I couldn't confirm it until today.
如果你把公司卖给我
If you sell me your company,
我就把这个送你做签约礼
I will give you this as a signing gift.
这是杀死你父母的凶手的名字
This is the name of the man who killed your parents...
还有书面证明  包括帮凶  动机
with documentary proof-- accomplices, motives,
原因  方式和身份
why, how and who.
我会整顿你的公司
I will fix your company,
保护你的遗产
protect your legacy
给你一个了结
and give you closure.
你父亲也会希望如此
It's what your father would've wanted.
这也是哥谭所亟需的
And what Gotham desperately needs.
今天之内给我回复
I need your answer by the end of the day.
吉姆
Hey, Jim?
高兴点
Cheer up.
你的冒险精神哪去了
Where's your spirit of adventure?
下个路口右转
Next right.
我知道这是个圈套
I know it's a trap.
你只是盖勒文手上的木偶
And Galavan's using you like a puppet.
一切都是盖勒文在幕后搞鬼  对吗
It is Galavan who's behind all this, right?
他就是个疯子  芭芭拉
He's a psychopath, Barbara.
他只是在利用你
He's using you.
他此刻正在嘲笑你呢
He's laughing at you.
等他利用完你
And when he's done with you,
你就成了累赘
you're just a loose end.
他会杀了你的
He'll kill you.
你还真不喜欢这个盖勒文啊
You really don't like this Galavan guy, do you?
她不会说实话的  吉姆
She's not talking, Jim.
我们现在就得掉头
We need to turn this car around now.
再给我一点时间
Just give me a little more time.
这样的葬礼可能不太正式
Well, I'm afraid this is as proper a burial
可我只能做到这样了
as circumstances allow.
但至少我们能最后再一起吃一餐
But I thought we could have one last meal together.
我本是个不完整的人  柯林格小姐
I was a broken man, Miss Kringle.
两个人格争执不休
Two halves at war with each other.
但多亏了你
But thanks to you,
我完整了
I am whole.
我不会忘记你的
I will not forget you.
入夜把你带走
I take you by night,
白天将你送回
by day take you back.
害怕失去我  而不是拥有我
None suffer to have me, but do from my lack.
猜猜我是什么
What am I?
那是个谜语吗
That some sort of riddle?
你不应该这么鬼鬼祟祟的
You know, you really shouldn't sneak up on people;
这不礼貌
that's not polite.
这里可不经常有人来
Not usually any people out here.
我可以请你吃点茶点三明治吗
Can I interest you in a tea sandwich?
什么
A what?
这里面是什么啊
What heck is in there?
这可好
Great.
只能另想办法了
Now I've got to improvise.
别乱跑哦
Don't go anywhere.
芭芭拉  听我说
Barbara, listen to me.
你在听吗
Are you listening?
你还有大好人生
You have a lifetime ahead of you.
别被疯狂毁了
Don't throw it away on madness.
戈登  布洛克  回话
Gordon, Bullock... Come in.
说吧  警监
Go ahead, Captain.
我不喜欢这情况  你们被围起来了
I don't like this. You're boxed in.
到处都是隐蔽的有利高地
There's lots of cover, high vantage points all or out.
埋伏的绝佳地点
Perfect spot for an ambush.
没错  你们得撤退
Yeah, I gotta pull you out.
现在掉头  你将一无所获
Turn around, you get nothing.
先别撤
Not yet.
听见没  你们得撤退
You hear me? I'm pulling you out.
说什么  警监  我听不到
What was that, Captain? You're breaking up.
布洛克  我发誓  你敢违抗...
Bullock! I swear to God, if you disobey...
芭芭拉  好好想想
Barbara, think hard.
别放弃大好人生
Don't throw away your life.
什么人生
What life?
你和我...
You and me...
我们曾有过美好人生
we had a life.
我们有过真情
We had real love.
你向我求婚
You asked me to marry you.
我订了教堂  买了婚纱
I booked a church. I bought a damn wedding dress.
吉姆  我也是傻
Jim... fool that I am,
即便是现在也还爱着你
I still love you, even now.
我知道你对我也还有感情
And I know you still have feelings for me,
这是你亲口说的
'cause you said so.
咱们待会儿再谈感情
We can talk about our feelings later.
现在有更要紧的事
There's more at stake here.
我爱你  吉姆
I love you, Jim.
我觉得  你内心深处
And I think, deep down,
也还爱着我
you still love me.
我的天  芭芭拉  我才不在乎...
Oh, for God's sakes, Barbara, I don't give a...
行动  行动
Move, move!
你要杀我吗  吉姆
You gonna shoot me, Jim?
设立20个街区的防线
I want a 20-block perimeter,
进行彻底搜查
with hard target searches
不放过任何一栋大楼  商家和酒水店
of every building, business and bodega.
搜查所有房间
We kick down everything with four walls and a roof.
找到他之前  谁都不许睡觉
Nobody sleeps until our boy gets home.
我叫你离开的
I told you to get out of here.
是吗
You did?
脑袋里还嗡嗡作响呢
Still a lot of ringing in my head.
我肯定是没听到
I must've missed it.
这是直接命令
This is a direct order.
你不属于这里了
You don't belong here anymore.
回家去
Go home.
好了
Okay.
这样吧
Well, let's see.
如果我不能把坑挖得更大
If I can't make the hole bigger,
那就把你变小点
then I'll make you smaller.
谁吃了我的三明治
Who has eaten my sandwich?
这么隐蔽的森林
For a secluded forest,
人流还真不少
this place sure has a lot of foot traffic.
看来里面要挤了
Looks like it's gonna get a tad crowded in there.
我就回来
I'll be back.
你在这儿啊  布鲁斯少爷
Ah, there you are, Master Bruce.
到处找你呢
Been looking all over the gaff for you.
这下面有点闷吧
Bit dreary down here, isn't it?
想吃点什么吗
Fancy something to eat?
怎么了
What's up?
我想问你个问题
I need to ask you a question.
你要保证会告诉我实话
And I need your word that you're going to be honest with me.
一向如此
I always am.
好吧  我保证
All right, you have my word.
我的训练
My training...
这些我需要的
the skills that I need
用来铲除韦恩集团腐败的技能
to take down the corruption at Wayne Enterprises.
要多久才能掌握
How long will it take?
这没有固定时间线啊
Well, there's no set timeline.
实在不是那样的啊
It doesn't really work like that, does it?
阿尔弗雷德  一年吗
Alfred. A year?
还是两年
Two years?
五年
Five?
要比那长多了
Well, a lot longer than that,
你才能成为你想做的那种人
for you to be the man that you need to be.
但你早晚会成功的  我保证
But you will get there, I promise you that.
但在此期间有多少人要受苦
Yeah, well, how many will suffer in the meantime?
有多少人要因我家族公司的
How many will die because of the crimes
罪行而死
committed by my family's company?
什么
What...
谁
Who...
你为什么会说这样的话  布鲁斯少爷
Where's all this coming from, Master Bruce?
我今早跟盖勒文市长谈过
I spoke to... Mayor Galavan this morning.
然后呢
And...?
他要我把我韦恩集团的股份卖给他
He wants me to sell him my shares in Wayne Enterprises
这样他才能...治理好公司
so he can... fix the company.
清理哥谭
Clean up Gotham.
这样啊
I see.
你瞒着我什么呢
And what aren't you telling me?
他说
He says...
他知道杀害我父母的人的身份
that he knows the identity of the man who killed my parents.
他想以此换公司  是吗
Which he's offering in return for the company, right?
是的
Yes.
但这...
Yeah, well, that's...
不算公平交换啊
not an offer, is it?
这是敲诈
That's bloody extortion.
但我还是不得不考虑  阿尔弗雷德
Yeah, well, I can't help but consider it, Alfred.
你不该考虑
Well, you shouldn't.
敲诈
There's a fine line
和谈判之间只有一线之隔
between extortion and negotiation.
是的  布鲁斯少爷  但总归是有道线
Yes, there is, Master Bruce, but there's still a line.
我父母被杀
My parents were killed
就是因为父亲试图制止腐败
because of the corruption that my father was trying to stop.
到目前为止
As of now, their...
他们的死根本白费了
their deaths have been in vain,
但如果盖勒文市长真能
but if Mayor Galavan can truly...
如果他真能治理好韦恩集团
if he can truly fix Wayne Enterprises,
那么我不是有道德责任
isn't it my moral... duty
让他那么做吗
to allow him to do so?
为了我父亲的遗志
For my father's legacy?
韦恩集团不是托马斯和玛莎·韦恩的遗志
Wayne Enterprises isn't Thomas and Martha Wayne's legacy.
他们的遗志就站在这里
That legacy is standing right here.
在我面前
With me.
阿尔弗雷德  我只希望这一切结束是不是不对
Alfred, am I wrong if I just want it all to be over?
我只希望这一切结束
I just want... I just want it to be over.
不不  你没什么不对
No, no. No, you're not wrong.
过来
Come here.
你没什么不对
You're not wrong.
是啊
I know.
居然还这么合身简直难以置信
Can you believe it still fits?
你记得
Do you remember
我们第一次来这里的情景吗
when we first visited this place?
我是多么激动
How excited I was
能在这里结婚
to get married here?
你觉得哥谭市警局找来之前你还能撑多久
How long do you think you have before the GCPD finds us?
你总这样
So typical.
我在说我们的事
I'm talking about us,
你却想着
and your head...
工作
...is in work.
根本没有"我们"
There is no "Us."
这都是干什么
What is all this?
这是我的婚纱
Well, this is my wedding dress.
裁缝还替我存着
The tailor still had it in storage.
多走运啊
I mean, can you believe the luck?
或是命运
Or fate.
那是卡拉翰神父
That's Father Callahan.
你还记得吧
You remember him, of course.
这几个
And these bozos...
不认识  但婚礼总得有人见证
Who knows? But you can't have a wedding without witnesses.
这是法律
That's the law.
芭芭拉
Barbara...
吉姆
Jim...
拜托别一副惊讶不爽的样子
please don't act all surprised and aggrieved.
你早知道
You knew,
从头就知道
from the start,
这是个陷阱
that this was a trap.
但你觉得
But you thought, "Hey,
"让坏人放马过来好了
let the bad guys take their best shot.
我可是吉姆·戈登
I'm Jim Gordon.
我会想办法获胜的
I'll find a way to win.
或是送命"
Or die."
现在是第二选项  亲爱的
It's option B, baby.
你最真挚的愿望成真了
Your fondest wish come true.
我才不想死
I don't want to die.
你当然想了
Sure you do.
隐藏真实的自己  你难道不厌倦吗
Aren't you tired of hiding your true self?
自欺欺人  难道不厌倦吗
Tired of lying to yourself?
欺骗小莱
To Lee?
我从不欺骗小莱
I don't lie to Lee.
是吗
Really?
那我们问问她吧
Let's ask her.
小莱
Lee!
好好享受吧
Savor every moment.
好啊  妹子
Hey, girlfriend.
我们真得好好谈谈这个坏小子
We really need to talk about this bad boy.
我们有过真情
We had real love.
你向我求婚
You asked me to marry you.
我订了教堂  买了婚纱
I booked the church. I bought a damn wedding dress.
吉姆
Jim...
我也是傻
fool that I am,
即便是现在也还爱着你
I still love you even now.
我订了教堂  买了婚纱
I booked the church. I bought a damn wedding dress.
每15分钟汇报一次消息
I want updates every 15 minutes.
等等
Hang on.
给我转身滚出去
Turn around and get the hell out of here.
-她带他去教堂了  -教堂  什么教堂
- She's taking him to church. - Church? What church?
她提到了他们没能结成的婚
She talked about the wedding they never had.
她想重来一次
She wants a do-over.
哥谭大教堂离绑架地点最近
Gotham Cathedral is nearest to the snatch site.
他们就在那里
That's where they are.
这太不靠谱了
That's thin.
我知道我没说错
I know I am right.
我再给你回电话
I'll call you back.
走吧
Let's go.
小莱  你觉得你和吉姆的感情进展如何
So, Lee, how do you think your relationship with Jim is going?
这事跟小莱无关  放她走
This doesn't concern Lee. Let her go.
这是你我之间的事
This is between you and me.
这
This...
是我们所有人的事
is about all of us.
她应该看清你的真面目
She deserves to know exactly who you are.
我了解他
I know who he is.
那怎么可能呢
Oh, how could you
他自己都看不清楚
when he doesn't even know?
他根本不会
He is incapable
诚实面对自己
of being honest with himself,
更别说诚实对待别人
let alone anyone else.
那你呢
What about you?
这一天都是谎言
This entire day has been a lie.
你根本没打算交出关于盖勒文的证据
You were never going to give up proof on Galavan.
谁
Who?
你想听实话吗
You want some honesty?
好啊
Fine.
詹姆斯市长活得好好的
Mayor James is alive and well
在中国港一间仓库里
at a stash house on China Docks.
怎么样
Hmm, see?
这不是说实话了
Honesty.
该你了
Now you.
谁把他关在那儿的
Who put him there?
真无聊  吉姆
Boring, Jim.
你所认识的吉姆·戈登只是假象
The Jim Gordon you know is an act.
他就像个瘾君子
He's like an addict
自以为能浅尝黑暗的滋味
who thinks he can dabble in darkness
只要不被人发现针孔就行
as long as nobody sees the needle marks.
人人都会装装样子
Everyone has an act.
他跟你说过  自己是怎么在哥谭市警局复职的吗
Did he tell you how he got reinstated at the GCPD?
他为企鹅杀了个人
He killed a man for Penguin.
真不错啊  吉姆
Very good, Jim.
你还真告诉她了
You did tell her.
我们之间没有秘密
We don't have secrets between us.
他做了很多他并不以为傲的事
He's done a lot of things that he's not proud of.
人人都如此
Everyone has.
但你还是爱他
But you love him anyway,
是吗
is that right?
尽管他有种种不是
Despite all his faults.
是的
Yes, I do.
好个小圣母  小莱医生
Cute little do-gooder Dr. Lee,
爱着一个残忍冷酷
in love with a cruel, cold,
痴迷于死亡的虐待狂
death-obsessed sadist.
吉姆不是那样的
That's not Jim.
你觉得你比我还了解他吗
Do you think you know him better than I do?
我也爱他的
I love him, too, you know.
我了解他
I know him
比你更了解
better than you do.
好吧  芭芭拉  我明白
Okay, Barbara, I hear you.
你爱他  我们都爱他
You love him. We both love him.
-没事的  -但我更爱他
- That's okay. - But I love him more.
听着  芭芭拉
Okay, listen, Barbara.
我现在明白了  求你
I know that now. Please...
我要证明我更爱他
I'm gonna prove that I love him more.
我要把你的漂亮脸蛋
I am going to carve your pretty face
从头骨上割下来
off your skull.
然后你们就都会明白
And then you will both understand
什么是真爱
what true love is.
还有件事
Okay, just one more thing.
什么
What?
你的婚纱
Your dress.
我好喜欢
I-I love your dress.
我只想知道你是在哪买的
I just want to know where you got it.
刀放下
Drop the knife.
瞧他出现了
There he is.
我的小恶魔
My little monster.
别逼我杀你
Don't make me kill you.
逼你
Make you?
吉姆
Jim,
你一直想
you long
杀我
to kill me.
动手吧  吉姆
Do it, Jim.
干掉我
Do me.
别再往前走了
Don't take another step.
杀了他
Kill him!
去抓她
Go get her!
吉姆
Jim!
结束了
It's over.
还没呢
Not yet.
撑住
Hold on.
对不起  亲爱的
I'm sorry, baby.
我真不是个好女伴
I've been kind of a bad date, huh?
我爱你  亲爱的
I love you, baby.
不要
No!
树篱和灌木接住了她
Some hedges and bushes broke her fall,
她骨头摔断一堆  还摔出了脑震荡
but she's got half a dozen broken bones and a concussion.
情况很危险
She's critical.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
嗯
Yeah.
现在不是时候  但这事结束后
Not now, but when this is over,
我们得谈谈
we need to talk.
我知道
I know.
你从她口里挖到东西了吧
Tell me you got something from her.
她没供出盖勒文
She didn't give up Galavan,
但她说詹姆斯市长还活着
but she did say Mayor James is alive.
被关在中国港的一间安全屋里
Stashed in a safe house on China Docks.
所有移动小队  立刻赶往中国港
All mobile units, China Docks, right now!
是  警监
Ten-four, Captain.
哥谭市警局
GCPD!
救命
Help.
这些人怎么回事啊
What is wrong with these people?
救命
Help me.
詹姆斯市长
Mayor James?
救救我
Help me, please.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
是谁干的
Who did this to you?
你以为呢
Who do you think?!
文件似乎都没问题了
All the papers seem to be in order.
你做的是正确的决定
You're making the right decision.
签字  这份文件就归你了
Sign, and the file is yours.
我改主意了
I... I changed my mind.
我不能卖掉我的公司
I can't sell you my company.
价码多高都不行
Not for any price.
阿尔弗雷德  快把布鲁斯从他身边带走
Alfred, get Bruce away from him now.
戈登警探
Detective Gordon?
你被捕了
You're under arrest.
没想到能见到我吗
Surprised to see me?
我能问问罪名是什么吗
May I ask what the charge is?
绑架折磨奥布雷·詹姆斯
The kidnapping and torture of Aubrey James.
铐上他
Cuff him.
把他带走
Get him out of here.
哪去了
Where?
不  不
No! No!
告诉我是谁杀了他们
Tell me who killed them!
求你
Please.
我愿付出一切
I'll do anything.
总算找到了
Finally.
天呐
Oh, my.
企鹅先生
Mr. Penguin?
救救我
Help me, please.